Đức Lê

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam



ducqhle@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ducqhle

Summary

Have 3 years of experience in software development. As a coder, I take responsibility and have high standards on my code. As a team member, I'm actively communicating, and collaborating with teammates, proactive discussion in brainstorming ideas and developing solutions. Contributed values by fulfilling assigned tasks with reusable and extendable solutions by high-quality code.

As a problem solver, I keep a positive attitude towards all challenges and always consider technologies as tools in order to solve problems better and better. I care about my product seem as I own it and want the best for my users. Had the business view, I figure out and focus on the most important thing at a time.

As a developer, I willing to changes for improvement and able to quickly adapt to new technologies.

Experience



📦 Full Stack Engineer

Spiderbox Design

Jan 2021 - Present (1 year 7 months +)

Closely and independently working with the co-worker's team from Australia to developing UX-UI for Energy products & Services website powered by ReactJS, React-Bootstrap, NextJS, and AWS services.

Maintain codebase quality by participated in reviewing code follow best practice, refactoring code into small and reusable components, adding Unit Tests to improve the coverage and increase maintainability for the product.

Participated in solution discussions of the business specifications. Proactively discuss the details and provide consultants to help increase user experience, resolving issues and bugs to improve the product's reliability.

Participated in developing mobile app using React Native and Redux, Sagas.

Participated in create business report using PowerBI and AWS Athena.



Software Engineer

mesoneer

Jul 2020 - Jan 2021 (7 months)

Participated in developing the core features for the chatbot-platform with NodeJS, TypeScript.

Participated in maintaining codebase quality.

Participated in researching, designing solutions in order to implement chatbot application requirements and systems required specifications.

Participated in configuring CI/CD process using Jenkins, Docker, and integrate with Bitbucket, OpenShift.

Participated in sharing knowledge and documenting technical specifications.

Technical stack details: NodeJS, TypeScript, FastCheck, React, Botkit, Microsoft Bot Framework, Jest, MongoDB, Docker, Jenkins, Rasa, Openshift.

Software Engineer

KMS Technology, Inc.

Sep 2018 - Apr 2020 (1 year 8 months)

Participated in grooming, sizing, and sending questions/solution reviews in order to clarify the project's requirements.

Participated in migrating a .NET legacy system from monolith to microservices by using AWS .NET core and NodeJS serverless services .

Directly supported the onshore-scrum team during the deployment process.

Delivered new packages to develop, staging, and production environments (back-end, front-end, DB) both manually through Windows Server or automatically by CI/CD process using blue-green deployment..

Technical stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ASP.NET Core, NodeJS, MSSQL, PostgreSQL, S3, CloudWatch, Lambda, Elastic Beanstalk, API Gateway, Route53, CloudFormation, Docker, Microsoft Bot Framework, LUIS, QnA Maker.

Education



University of Science

Bachelor's degree, Information Technology

2015 - 2018

Learned software development fundamental.

Learned soft skills for teamwork, self-planing and self-management.

Learned AI fundamental algorithms.

Licenses & Certifications



FEFSET Quick English Check - Score: Advanced (CEFR C1/C2) - EF Education First



KMS - Techcon Certificate of Appreciation - KMS Technology, Inc.

- **Udemy Certificate of Completion Learn and Understand NodeJS** Udemy UC-0fe2e8a4-27d6-48b0-8ce8-44bf8c75705d/
- React The Complete Guide (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux) Udemy UC-423a048a-5956-41fd-b234-2155f2966d5c

Skills

Node.js • .NET Core • React • Chatbots • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • Scrum • Multithreading • Research • Technical Documentation • Front-end Development